# Roman Cinis

# Google-awarded Staff Mobile Engineer

#### CONTACT

tsinis.job@gmail.com

Brno, Czech Republic github.com/tsinis linkedin.com/in/tsinis

### **AWARDS**

- by <u>Google</u> in the official
   Flutter Contest "Flutter
   Puzzle Hack" (2022)
- by <u>Google & Lenovo</u> in the <u>official Flutter</u>
   Contest "Flutter Clock"
- <u>Dribbble</u> Player (2020)
- in <u>European Healthcare</u>
   Hackathon (2021)
- in the Official Flutter

  Community Hackathon

#### **EDUCATION**

Information Technology 18-20-M/01

Secondary Technical School AGC a. s. Teplice, Czech Republic

#### **SKILLS**

- Flutter & Dart
- Git & CI/CD
- REST API & Firebase
- Unit/Wiget/E2E Tests
- TS, Swift & Objective-C

#### CAREER SUMMARY

My career began in graphic design, gradually expanding into various design disciplines. After a decade dedicated to design, specializing in UX/UI, I leveraged my earlier exposure to IT to transition into SW development in 2018. My initial freelance Flutter projects laid a solid foundation, but I sought the challenges of a larger team. At Bindworks, I contributed to complex medical apps, honing my skills. Eager for new challenges and international exposure, I joined CarOnSale, advancing to a Staff Mobile Engineer role.

Previously, I showcased my skills through Flutter competition wins, but now I prioritize family & open-source outside of work.

## **EXPERIENCE** (last 13 years)

#### • STAFF MOBILE ENGINEER

CarOnSale | Berlin (Remote) | JUNE 2022 - PRESENT Owned the company's mobile development. Mentored new COS mobile engineers. Established best practices, and implemented linting, CI/CD, and other integrations.

Interesting numbers: Over the past two years, enhancements to the inspection application have led to a significant increase in inspections – from 1500 to over 5000 (per month).

#### FLUTTER DEVELOPER

Bindworks | Prague (Remote) | FEB. 2021 – JUNE 2022

Developed critical health-tech applications for major hospitals. Demonstrated expertise in handling sensitive patient information while prioritizing accessibility.

Interesting numbers: Managing extensive patient data (i.e. over 700000 Apple Watch health records from a single patient to store and process in the background on a mobile device).

• FLUTTER DEVELOPER (2018+) & UX/UI DESIGNER (2014+)

Freelance | Brno | MAY 2014 - MARCH 2021

### • SENIOR GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Danielson | Louny | AUGUST 2011 - APRIL 2014